Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Peace.
Long ago. before The Founders
established this great city of ours.
that word was all but meaningless.
An ideal as elusive as a dream.
Now. 200 years later.
we are. all of us. living proof
that peace is indeed attainable.
The reason for this is.
of course. our Faction System.
Erudite. Dauntless. Amity.
Candor. Abnegation.
In dividing people according
to personality and aptitude.
we've created a society in which
each faction plays a critical role
in maintaining the social order.
But this harmony we've
achieved is now under attack
from a small but extremely dangerous group
of individuals-
We call them Divergents.
They are. in essence.
the worst of what humanity used to be.
Rebellious. defiant and uncontrollable.
Five days ago. a rogue group of Divergents.
posing as Dauntless
brutally invaded Abnegation.
An obvious attempt
to cripple the Faction System
by attacking it's most vulnerable members.
These Divergents despise our system
because they are incapable
of conforming to it.
These latest rumors. for example.
that I was somehow behind
the attack on Abnegation?
Nothing more than Divergent propaganda.
I am devoting myself
to bringing these fugitives to justice.
I've exercised my right
as acting Council leader...
...to declare martial law
until I'm confident that any threat
to our security has been eliminated.
Tell Jeanine we got it.
We are all
that is left of humanity.
The vast wall that encloses this city
may protect us from our toxic surroundings.
but it is up to us to confront
any element that could
poison us from within.
Because. when you are
civilization's last hope.
peace is not merely an ideal.
It is an obligation.
And it is up to all of us to take a stand
against it's one true enemy.
Divergents.
Amity.
We need to make sure it's clear.
Tris!
Help us. Please help us. Please.
Please help us.
You have to help us.
Sorry. you have to leave.
You just don't belong here.
It's all her fault.
You killed Will.
No.
She killed him.
She killed him. She killed him.
Mama.
You killed us all.
Will!
And three!
Higher!
Hey.
Higher! Higher!
Wanna go higher?
All right. everyone. back to class.
Let's go.
Okay. Here we go.
See ya. Bye.
I just wanted to do something different.
Yeah.
Well. it's definitely different.
You don't like it?
No. I like it. I like it a lot.
I'm just surprised. that's all.
What's goin' on. Tris?
Nothin'. I'm fine. Just...
Still having nightmares?
No.
We're good.
You and me.
I know nothing else is. But we are.
Good morning.
and have a blessed day.
Time for chores.
All planters. report to the dome.
All planters to the dome.
How much longer
do we have to stay here. Four?
Until we know
it's safe to leave.
Hey.
Hi.
Son...
You can't ignore me forever.
I know you're thinkin'
about your next move.
but there are things you don't know.
Marcus. please just leave us alone.
Your mother didn't come back
to Abnegation just to save you.
She died trying to hide
something from Jeanine.
Something that was entrusted
to Abnegation a long time ago.
Marcus. stop.
Whatever you want from us.
you're not gonna get it.
I'm not the enemy here.
You found it.
It was in the home
of Natalie and Andrew Prior.
like you said.
Mind telling me what's inside?
A message from The Founders
that will ensure
the future our people deserve.
Divergents will destroy our society.
Unless we destroy them.
And now we can.
However. only a Divergent
can open this box.
Find them. Every last one of them.
Go with happiness.
- Go with happiness.
- Thank you.
Go with happiness.
I really don't know how much longer
I can do this whole peace and love thing.
It's the Amity way. all right?
We're just trying to blend in.
I'm trying to blend in.
It's just not working.
Comin' through on your right.
Okay. here we go.
Hey. look. a rainbow.
- Oh.
- It's pretty.
Go with happiness.
Virtual pathological friendliness
with unquestioned passivism?
I love this place.
Thank you. Go with happiness.
Oops. excuse me.
Hey. Tris. I really like your hair. by the way.
Did you try to cut it all short
and weird like that?
Peter. why don't you take
your food and sit down. huh?
Or what?
Besides. I think we should all
stick together now that we're
- all officially fugitives.
- Shh.
Wait. what do you mean.
"officially fugitives"?
- Oh. you don't know?
- Let's go. let's go.
You didn't tell Caleb?
Yeah. so now Jeanine is saying
that the attack on Abnegation
was orchestrated by a group
of renegade Divergents
and their sympathizers.
So then they're blaming
this whole thing on us?
Yeah. Jeanine needed a reason to petition
the Council to institute martial law.
Now she has one.
Staying here at Amity
is still our best option for now.
We need to keep an ear to the ground.
Find out where the rest
of the Dauntless are.
Then we can make a move.
We need to kill Jeanine.
I know.
But we're not ready yet.
Beatrice. you're not being serious. right?
No. I am being serious.
I'm not gonna stop until she's dead.
Tris. you can't just go
around killing people.
No. she's right.
Listen to your sister.
Tris. I think you should go to Erudite
and kill Jeanine yourself.
I'll stay with Caleb so that
you don't get him killed. too.
What?
Come on. you know.
Like you did your parents.
Come on!
What do you think you're doing?
My office. Now.
Enjoy your meal. everyone.
Enjoy your meal.
Calm down.
Just calm down.
Was I not clear that the terms
of your sanctuary here
included nonviolence?
I can guarantee you nothing like this
will ever happen again.
Well. be that as it may.
you can no longer stay here with us.
Your presence is just too disruptive.
Truth is that our sanctuary
was never gonna last
very long here anyways.
Was it?
With you not standing up to Jeanine.
You don't understand us at all.
No. I do understand you.
I understand that you think
you can stay out of this.
But you can't.
One day she's gonna show up and
Jeanine is gonna take whatever power
you think you have away from you.
Tris. Tris...
Look. Johanna.
we need a little more time.
I need to find out where
the rest of the Dauntless are.
Then we can leave.
And then what?
Attack Erudite?
I will not be a party to violence.
And no one's asking you to.
We just need a few more days.
One.
One what?
One more chance.
See. to be Amity is to forgive.
Others. And yourself.
You're hurting. Tris.
And my heart goes out to you.
I know what it's like to stand helpless
while you lose the ones you love.
But killing Jeanine is not going to
bring your mother back.
I know you're angry.
But you're letting it consume you.
What is it?
Stay here.
And keep quiet.
Gentlemen.
Amity welcomes you.
To what do we owe the pleasure?
This isn't really a social call. Johanna.
We're looking for Divergents.
I see. Well. of course.
anything we can do to help.
Gonna need you to volunteer
your faction to be tested.
New screening technology
- from Erudite.
- Amity...
Now that Jeanine's heading up the Council.
the approval process just got a little easier.
You're exceeding your jurisdiction.
Now. Johanna. what happened
to that Amity politeness?
The easy way or the hard way?
It's up to you.
All right.
But under protest.
Okay. we're good to go!
Move it out! Round 'em up.
In the dome.
All Amity report to the dome
for new mandatory testing.
Please proceed to the dome
for mandatory testing.
In the building.
Let's go. Get inside.
Line up.
Let's go. Move it.
This way.
Line it up.
Building secured.
You know something. lady?
You seem awfully stuck in that doorway.
Eric's here.
We need to move now. Come on.
What's up there?
- Wait. stop.
- Just my office.
Go. go. go!
Hmm.
Hey.
There's two guards with guns.
We're going out the window?
We need to split up.
Okay. yeah. Okay.
Every man for themselves.
Good.
- Hey. they're up here! Hey!
- Go. go. go. go!
Eric. they're up here!
Come on. they're getting away!
All right. you ready?
Let's go.
- Where?
- Out the window.
I got three on foot making
a break toward the dome.
- Divergent.
- Got one.
I repeat.
three on foot toward the dome.
Over there!
- I demand amnesty!
- Get down! Now!
I'm the leader of Abnegation!
It is my right!
Detain him!
- Whoa. Okay. All right.
- Let's go.
Oh. oh. Ow.
Come on.
Come on. keep moving.
Come on!
Come on.
Let's go!
Keep going. Come on.
- Listen!
- What?
Train!
Go. go. go!
Go! Come on!
Caleb!
Keep moving!
Go!
Ammo!
Come on. come on! Go! Go! Move!
Move! Go. go. go!
Caleb!
Move!
Oh. you folks sure know
how to make an entrance.
Factionless.
Amity?
But you stand like Dauntless.
No idea what this one is.
Look. we just need to get
to the city. that's all.
Well. too bad. Train's taken.
And you damaged our cargo.
These are
Abnegation fabric bolts.
And you're Factionless. right?
- Caleb.
- I used to be Abnegation.
We used to use those same bolts
to make clothes for you.
You're saying that we're stealing from you?
No. No. no. no.
I'm no longer Abnegation.
So technically you're
not stealing from me. but...
No. you're not stealing at all.
I mean. maybe.
It's a question of semantics. I suppose.
whether it's stealing or charity.
But it's all really the same.
That's enough! Get off!
Everybody. relax.
All right. you made your point.
We'll get off your train. all right?
Got you.
Will just everybody relax. okay?
Why don't we. uh. take a seat!
Caleb!
- Stop!
- I'm sorry.
- I was just trying to help.
- Don't!
Oh. yeah. this is gonna be fun. isn't it?
Everybody. just calm down. All right?
Oh.
Caleb.
Ahhh!
No!
Get off of me! Get off!
You all right? You okay?
Yeah.
Tobias Eaton.
You say that again.
What? You know him?
I am him.
We have been looking for you.
Four. what are they talking about?
Four.
Follow me.
Tris.
I'm sorry. I wanted to help...
Four.
Four. why are they looking for you?
How do they know your name?
This is Factionless?
This is insane.
Tobias.
Mother.
I thought she was dead.
Me too.
Someone please tell me
what's going on here.
Tobias' father was very abusive.
I knew the only way
I could ever truly escape him
would be to disappear completely.
Abnegation helped me fake my death.
Anything to protect Marcus' image.
But you just left him
there alone with Marcus?
I was very young.
I reached out to him about a year ago.
I felt it was finally time to reconnect.
I'm still your mother.
No. my mother's dead.
I went to her funeral when I was six.
And she wasn't trying to reconnect with me.
She was trying to use me. like you are now.
Why?
She wants an army.
An army?
I want an alliance.
No. what you want is revenge.
This isn't about me.
It's about putting an end to a system that
says one group is more deserving than another.
This city may be surrounded by a wall.
but it doesn't have to be a prison.
- I think that's a bit extreme.
- Hmm?
I mean. the Faction System isn't perfect.
but it's hardly a prison.
Let me guess. Erudite.
I was Erudite.
You willing to kill Jeanine?
Absolutely.
When I was married to Marcus.
I knew her well.
And believe me.
there's nothing she isn't capable of.
But I think you already know that.
Tris. we can't trust her.
Or maybe she knows...
We're on the same side. Tris.
I'm Factionless because
I don't fit into any one faction.
And you're Divergent because
you belong to too many.
But we're both a threat to Jeanine.
My people are ready for war.
if that's what it takes.
And then what?
We depose those in power.
And once you've done that?
Once you've killed Jeanine.
who's in power then?
See. that's the part
that she always conveniently leaves out.
Don't you tell me this isn't about you.
This is only about you.
I know where the remaining
Dauntless are hiding.
Where?
They took shelter in Candor.
As far as I know. they're still there.
Think about it.
If we were to combine forces.
Dauntless and Factionless.
we'd be unstoppable.
That's not gonna happen.
Thank you for your hospitality.
but we'll be leaving in the morning.
Four. maybe this is...
Tobias. please. reconsider.
Don't you call me that.
My name's Four.
You wanna tuck him in. or should I?
Well. this... This meal looks lovely.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I should have told you about her.
No more secrets. Okay?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to wake you.
I always loved watching him sleep.
I take it you're setting out
for Candor in the morning?
Yeah.
Listen. I only want what's best for him.
You hardly even know him.
You'd like to think that. wouldn't you?
But deep down. I think you're scared
I know him all too well.
I'm not scared.
Of course you are.
You're scared he'll finally see you
for what you really are.
Deadly.
You don't believe me?
Ask him.
You okay?
Yeah.
You sure?
I'm not coming with you guys.
What?
To Candor.
I'm not coming with you guys.
What are you talking about?
What's your plan?
You guys are gonna find
the rest of Dauntless. Then what?
You attack Erudite. assassinate Jeanine.
start a civil war?
I'm sorry. I'm just not...
I'm not cut out for that.
I'm not like you guys.
I need to go back to Abnegation. maybe.
Sort out what our parents left behind.
At least I'd be useful there.
Caleb. there's nothing left at Abnegation.
Yeah.
You okay?
Just need to get to Candor.
Tris.
I know you think Caleb
is your responsibility.
but he made his own choice.
You can't protect everyone.
I can't protect anyone.
Nobody can.
Him leaving isn't your fault.
None of this is your fault.
Johanna was right.
You have to forgive yourself.
Thank you.
All factions
have been instructed to
- maintain a strict curfew until further notice.
- We gotta move.
Repeat.
All factions have been instructed
to maintain a strict curfew
until further notice.
- We found them.
- Yeah.
Four!
Damn. is it good to see you guys.
How are you. Uriah?
I'm better now.
I'm not exactly built for laying low.
- Tris!
- Christina.
- It's so good to see you.
- You too.
Have you heard anything about Will?
- No.
- Nothing?
No.
Something must have happened to him.
He would have found me by now. you know?
- Hey.
How you holdin' up?
How many Dauntless do we have?
Hundred and seventy-five. Total.
Hundred and seventy-five? That's it?
The rest followed Max.
Not near the numbers we need.
- No.
- Hold it!
Drop your guns.
Whoa. hey.
They're with us.
We know who you are.
Last warning. Drop your guns.
FOUR; All right.
Easy.
I'm Jack Kang.
I'm leadership here.
Yeah. we know who you are.
And we're not a threat to Candor.
That might be your truth.
It's not necessarily mine.
All I know for certain
is you're both wanted
for criminal insurgency and conspiring
in the attack on Abnegation.
Those are lies.
If you were Candor.
I would take you at your word.
Unfortunately. given the circumstances.
I'm obliged to hand you
over to the Council.
You can make your case there.
You might as well just kill us now.
If Jeanine finds us.
we're not gonna live to stand trial.
I doubt that very much.
She would never supersede the Council.
Sure about that?
Who's gonna stop her? You?
Factional law must be upheld.
All right. wait. wait. wait.
Can I ask you one question?
Jeanine believes that Erudite
are most fit to govern
because they are the smartest.
Do you believe that Candor is most fit
to judge because you're so honest?
I admit I do hold that belief.
Then would you say that
a trial held here at Candor
would be inherently more fair
than a trial held by Erudite?
Hmm.
The answer is yes.
In my opinion. a Candor trial would have
the greatest chance of
achieving true justice.
So are you asking me to
petition the Council
to grant Candor sole judiciary power?
No. As part of Candor's initiation.
you administer a truth serum.
Correct?
We don't typically discuss
such matters out of faction.
That's a pretty evasive answer.
Evasion is not dishonest.
It's not exactly honesty either.
Yes. We possess such a serum.
Then use it on us.
- Four.
- If we're guilty.
we'll surrender to the Council. All right?
If not. you've just saved two lives.
And made some loyal allies.
All right.
But you should know
that the serum can be quite brutal.
It was designed for Candor applicants
who are already predisposed to honesty.
Not everyone finds it so easy
to share their secrets.
Don't wanna do this.
We have to.
Neither of us have secrets worth dying for.
May the truth set you free.
Tobias Eaton.
you are accused of conspiring
with your fellow Dauntless
in the attack on Abnegation.
Is this true?
Conspiring. no.
But I did attack.
I was in a simulation controlled by Jeanine
and the rest of the Dauntless
that she recruited.
Tris found me.
She managed to break me free
from the simulation.
and then together we...
Together we fought our way out.
So you're saying
that Jeanine orchestrated this attack?
Yes.
One last thing.
If you suspected that Jeanine
had corrupted Dauntless.
why didn't you just leave?
Why did you stay?
I wanted to leave.
But I fell in love with Tris Prior.
And I couldn't leave her.
Thank you for your candor.
Tobias Eaton.
this trial is concluded.
And you are absolved of guilt
in the attack on Abnegation.
Miss Prior. if you would.
May the truth set you free.
Tris Prior.
Mr. Eaton said you managed
to free him from the sim.
Yes.
So you were never
under the simulation yourself?
No.
How is that possible?
Because I'm Divergent.
I see.
So you never harmed
any of your fellow Dauntless
or the Abnegation?
I did.
Both.
Who?
My mom.
Um...
I watched her die first.
And then my dad.
They were killed trying to save me.
And... I...
Miss Prior. the more you resist.
the more painful the serum will be.
Ow!
My friend...
I killed my friend.
He was trying to shoot me. And I...
I shot him first.
What was his name?
I can't.
Will.
I killed Will.
'Cause that's what happens
to people when they get close to me.
They get hurt or they die.
I can't forgive myself.
Thank you for your candor.
Tris.
I'm sorry. all right?
I told you that I didn't wanna do that.
Hey...
- Christina...
- Go.
Go.
Abnegation sim complete.
Dauntless sim initiating.
Ma'am. the Divergent's
vitals are dropping.
If we don't pull her out of
the sim soon. we'll lose her.
You'll stop when I say so.
She's gonna do it.
She's gonna pass the sim.
Dauntless sim failed.
Divergent Test Subject Six
is no longer viable.
All right. shut it down.
Wasting our time.
I've been assuming that
all Divergents are the same.
But some are much stronger than others.
Assign all non-essential personnel
to the Divergent detail.
We need to look harder.
We need to find that very special one.
Where's your scary boyfriend?
Probably off doing scary boyfriend things.
Mind if I join you?
I love heights.
From up here.
it all just seems so much smaller.
you know?
I know it sounds crazy.
but sometimes I think
I see lights out beyond the wall.
I know they say
it's all just wasteland out there. but...
We can't be the only ones left.
Can we?
Let's go!
Closest weapons?
Ground floor.
Floor's clear. Movin' down.
Mommy? Mommy?
Shh.
They hurt my mommy?
Look. I got one. too.
See? It's okay.
It's just the thing that
made everybody go to sleep.
Okay. I need you to do me a favor.
I need you to go to the top
of those stairs up there.
Don't come down until your
mommy comes to get you.
- Don't come down?
- Don't come down.
Can you do that?
Be brave. okay?
Okay. Go.
Hey.
Why are we the only ones awake?
Because we're Divergents.
Come on. I need your help.
We have to open this.
Uriah. I need your help.
Go.
Hey!
Look who decided to show up.
It's really good to see you again.
All right. folks.
Nothin' to be nervous about.
Just a little routine inspection.
Then we can all go back to our business.
Hello.
Divergent.
- 10%.
- Hmm.
Shit.
You're almost normal.
That's boring.
That is not part of the mission.
So what?
Far as I'm concerned
the rest of them are still outlaws.
Let's just wrap this up quickly.
The others are gonna be awake soon.
Hi. sweetie.
I shouldn'ta...
Divergent. 40%.
I'm afraid it's not you. either.
The lady said I shouldn'ta...
The lady said I shouldn'ta come downstairs.
Guess you shoulda listened.
Enough.
We still have to test her.
Eric!
Jeanine told us that
we have to test everyone.
Divergent. 100%.
I'll be damned.
What?
She's what we've been looking for.
Bullshit.
Divergent. 100%.
Get her in a vehicle.
I'll alert Jeanine.
If you think you got lucky. you're wrong.
You're gonna wish I killed you.
Drop it. Don't move.
- Drop your weapon!
- Get down.
- Let me see your hands.
- Right there!
Hey.
Thank you.
It's lucky you got that gun. Four.
Oh. we both know you were
never much without one.
You think she's safe now?
You're wrong.
Jeanine's never gonna stop
searching for you.
Why?
What does she want with her?
Tell me.
Look. all I know is she's
exactly what Jeanine needs.
She's the perfect subject.
Was that supposed to scare me?
You're responsible for the
death of hundreds of people.
You know the punishment for that.
Listen...
I've found a way to live with
the blood on my hands.
But can you?
Why won't they come out?
All I know is it put me in a sleeping sim.
and then I woke up to all
hell breaking loose.
Hec! Don't play with it.
You all know what this means.
Thank you. For helping us.
I wish I could do more.
I had no idea Jeanine was capable
of something like this.
It's time we fight back.
We don't have the numbers.
We will. Once we get to Factionless.
Strict curfew until further notice.
You heard Eric.
Jeanine's never gonna
stop coming after you.
It's our only option.
Tris Prior.
Of course.
It had to be her.
Is she still off the grid?
Yeah. But I think I found a solution.
It's Peter. Right?
Yeah. And. Jeanine.
can I just say that it is truly an honor
to finally meet you in person?
Congratulations. Mother.
You got your war.
I know you wish there was another way.
But there isn't.
I'm the lesser of two evils. Is that it?
You'd better be.
Tell me.
why did you surrender to Erudite?
What do you want?
I would like a position in your regime.
Ideally. I would like a position
with some advancement opportunities.
I may be Dauntless.
but I'm not just a meathead.
No offense. Max.
Prove your worth to us.
Then we can discuss your ambitions.
Great. When do I start?
Let's talk about your friend Tris Prior.
How do I flush her out?
Simple.
The girl's a walking bleeding heart.
She was born Abnegation.
That's her weak spot.
You just have to know how to press it.
Help! Come quick!
It's coming from up there.
Christina!
Please. help!
Somebody do something!
- Look!
- On the ledge!
The traitor Tris Prior
must be surrendered to Erudite
or every day more deaths will follow.
Go!
Hand over Tris Prior
or every day more deaths will follow.
Get down!
Hector! No!
Hand over Tris Prior
or every day
- more deaths will follow.
- Christina!
No!
Christina! Christina!
Tris. help me.
Tris!
It's okay.
We removed this from
the body of the suicide.
Marlene. Her name was Marlene.
I'm sorry. Marlene.
It's a very sophisticated
sim serum injector.
It also has a radio
transmitter in its head.
How do we get them out?
I don't know.
This tech was built to defend itself.
This tendril wraps around
the nearest major artery.
Try to remove them and they kill the host.
So what do we do?
Tori has to find a way
to neutralize the disks
before we do anything else.
Or we could do the logical thing.
And we hand her over.
Nobody knows about this alliance.
We have to protect that advantage.
If we hand Tris over now.
might buy us some time.
I think it's a good idea.
- Get rid of her!
- Damn right.
Except you'll have to go through me first.
Me. too.
And all of us.
Hey! I ain't the one with
the time bomb in my arm.
Yeah!
I know what you're thinking.
But I'm not gonna let you do it.
I can't let anyone else die because of me.
No one else is gonna die because of you.
Tori's gonna find a way
to disable the disks...
And if she doesn't?
Then... Then...
Then if she doesn't. we figure it out.
Together.
You know I'm just one person.
I'm not worth it.
No. you are worth it.
You are worth it to me.
I love you.
...plays a critical
role in maintaining the social order.
But this harmony we've
achieved is now under attack.
This city may be safely
enclosed behind a vast wall.
But make no mistake.
that wall alone does not
ensure our security.
It is up to us. every one of us.
to remain vigilant in identifying and isolating
any potential threat to our stability.
There are individuals hiding among us
who must be contained.
So permit me to address the objections
of my fellow faction leaders.
I am aware that there
have been some concerns
about the unavoidable raid on Candor.
So let me be clear.
The harboring of Divergents by any faction
cannot be tolerated.
Very soon. I will be presenting
what I believe to be no less than a mandate
from The Founders themselves.
And this will. I have no doubt.
validate the measures
I'm taking to keep the peace.
And provide the instructions
that will allow us
to eradicate the Divergent
crisis. once and for all.
Where are you going?
Tris left. She's gone.
What? When?
Last night.
Wait.
Tobias!
People look to you for leadership.
You can't just abandon them.
Tobias!
Wow.
I have to admit.
I'm impressed.
I mean. I knew that you were dumb.
but I didn't think that
you were dumb enough
to actually come down here
and turn yourself in.
The killings have to stop.
Well. that just goes to show that
you can take the girl outta Abnegation.
but you can't take
the Abnegation outta the girl.
Let's go.
Once a stiff. always a stiff. right?
What is this?
This is the only reason why you're alive. Tris.
Man. I love knowing stuff that you don't.
Need you to open up that box. Tris.
The only way to open that box
is to pass the sims
of all five factions.
But the only people that
have tried to do it so far
have died.
Oops.
I don't think I was
supposed to tell you that.
Oh. well.
No pressure.
Remarkable.
Chances of it being you. of all people.
Nearly defies the laws of probability.
As remarkable as the amount
of people you've managed
to murder.
Dark times call for extreme measures.
You may find it hard to believe.
but I am serving the greater good.
Step up on the disk. please.
Ma'am?
Hmm?
Oh.
Stop the suicides or
I swear I will shoot him.
That's okay. You can kill him if you want.
We have plenty of guards.
What?
I'm guessing you need me alive
for this to work.
Right?
Beatrice.
Caleb.
I...
Don't engage the subject.
Conditions are already less than optimal.
Oh. my God.
If I do this. the suicides stop?
No. The suicides will continue
until you succeed.
And pass all five sims.
Should be incentive enough.
Good luck.
Let's begin.
Initializing Dauntless sim.
Mom.
Tris. help me!
What? No!
Tris?
Mom!
Her heart rate is rising.
Keep her in play.
Mom!
- Tris!
- I'm coming!
Mom!
I'm coming.
Tris. help me!
Hold on.
Hold on!
Tris.
Dauntless sim complete.
Mom.
I miss you so much.
Mmm. I know you do.
But I'm still with you.
You need to be strong now.
Tell me you're gonna be strong.
I'm trying.
You can do this.
I know you can.
You're brave.
Braver than anyone.
I'm not brave. Mom.
I pretend that I am.
And I want people to think that I am.
But I'm not.
I'm really. really scared.
That maybe we are actually
what's wrong in this world.
Divergents.
I never wanted any of this.
You and Dad and Caleb and then Four.
And I can't help but think
that if I was normal
we would all still be together.
Mom. I don't wanna be Divergent anymore.
I just wanna feel safe again.
Candor sim complete.
Four.
You're here. Yeah?
Yeah. I am.
You're here.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Secure the hallway.
All right. Let's get you outta here.
- You good?
- Yeah.
Stop. Let him go.
Wait. you're not gonna shoot me?
Once a stiff. always a stiff.
Go!
Four. how did you get past security?
You know me.
Scary boyfriend skills.
What is it?
You weren't there.
You didn't even hear that.
Tris. we need to leave now. all right?
I'm sorry. Four.
What?
I'm sorry I didn't tell
you that I was gonna go.
I wanted to say goodbye
and I just didn't know how.
I didn't know how.
What are you talking about?
So even though I didn't
get to say it in real life
at least I get to say it now.
Even if it is just in the sim.
Tris. we're not in a sim.
Don't you think I'd know
if I was in a sim?
Four.
you're not in a sim.
You are the sim.
Wait. wait.
Erudite sim complete.
There's only Amity now.
She hasn't passed Abnegation yet.
Yes. she has.
When she spared your life.
This girl is extraordinary.
She's tested positive
for four factions in one day.
No one's gotten that far.
We've got a problem.
She's crashing.
We have to rest her.
Sure you're not letting familial attachment
cloud your judgment?
See for yourself.
Very well.
Detach the subject.
Good work. everyone.
We'll resume tomorrow.
You were never planning on
going back to Abnegation.
were you?
I had to do what I felt was right.
Our parents would be ashamed of you.
Well. maybe not.
I mean. I am willing to sacrifice you.
the only family I have left.
the only person I love.
in order to preserve
what's best for everyone else.
What's more selfless than that?
What does Jeanine think
is in that box. Caleb?
It's a message from The Founders.
But the box was to be opened
only if the Faction System broke down.
which is why it requires
someone like you to open it.
You are living proof
that the Divergent problem
has grown beyond all control.
Do you even hear
what you're saying right now?
No one thinks it's your fault
that you were born this way.
Jeanine murdered an entire faction. Caleb.
That faction could no longer be trusted.
She killed our parents.
Our parents brought that on themselves.
What are you talking about?
The box?
It was in their house.
They were the ones hiding it.
All of those lives could have been spared.
Seems we didn't know our parents
as well as we thought we did.
All right. Family reunion's over.
It's time to go.
I got a little surprise for you. Tris.
Four?
Tris!
- Tris! Tris!
- Four! Four!
- Tris!
Stop! Four!
Four!
I gather your brother
explained to you how vital
the work you're doing here
is to the future of this city?
Please. just let Four go.
If his well-being is of such concern
then you should focus on the task at hand.
Tell me. do you appreciate irony?
You tested positive for Erudite.
so you must have the intellectual capacity.
Irony?
For instance.
right now you're filled with hate.
But you need to pass an Amity sim.
Then there are other ironies at work. too.
Such as the fact that
your cherished mother...
Don't.
...who you so dauntlessly saved in the sim
is the reason you're
in this mess to begin with.
You're the reason I'm in this mess.
Then there's the most
poignant irony of all...
Stop.
...that Natalie Prior not only died
trying to protect the data that
- I now have in my possession.
- Because you stole it from her.
You killed her for it!
Data that she so selfishly withheld.
But her own daughter.
Her beloved Divergent Tris
is going to be the
one to deliver it to me.
I said stop!
Therefore. your mother's death.
just like your boyfriend's death.
will mean absolutely nothing.
Don't pull her out.
Not yet.
No.
Bring her back!
No!
Bring her back! Come on!
Come on.
Bring her back!
Test Subject Seven is no longer viable.
I really thought you were the one.
We'll just...
We'll just have to resume our search.
Find solace in your faction. Caleb.
We're your family now.
Jeanine wanted me to show you this.
Hey. Four. Maybe do that thing you do?
Hey. Four. come on.
that was pretty good. right?
First. I swiped a paralytic
from the infirmary.
Then I shot her up when she was all
freakin' out about you.
I mean. I told these guys
I was pretty smart.
Guess they shoulda listened.
You're real.
Yeah. I'm real.
What are you doing here?
You die. I die.
Okay. guys. come on.
Let's go. seriously.
We can do that later.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Thank you. Peter.
Yeah. whatever.
Now we're even. stiff.
All right.
Come on. let's go.
Before Jeanine realizes you're still alive.
- No. no. no.
- What?
The box.
We have to get the box.
What. are you kidding me?
Now's not the time for a souvenir. Tris.
Four. you have to listen to me.
It's not what Jeanine thinks it is.
I know it's not.
My mother would have destroyed it.
We have to get it.
Peter. is there another way into the lab?
I mean. I'd have to go
into the control room
to disable all the doors.
Okay. good. then do that.
Okay. Right now?
Yeah.
You just chose our side.
whether you meant to or not.
If you wanna survive. make sure we do.
Let's go.
Fuck.
Ma'am. our current assessment
with other possible candidates.
Correct. Female.
And we have the two males
introduced to you before?
No guns. It'll draw too much attention.
Hey.
Hold up.
Access denied.
Come on. come on.
Access granted.
All right. let's go.
Come on.
- Is that it?
- Yes.
All right. grab it and let's go.
Security breach.
Security breach. Lockdown.
What's going on?
What's going on? What is it?
There's been a breach in the sim room.
Get me a remote feed.
I wanna see who the hell is in there.
The cameras are down in the sector. too.
I'm sending guards there now. Let's go.
Bring up every cell. Now.
Show her.
Tori finally found a way
to get 'em out safely.
How many others?
Every last one.
Let's go.
South corridor. 40 yards down.
Tris?
Tris. come on. we gotta move.
Tris. we have to move.
I can't. I can't.
My mom died protecting
whatever's inside of this.
I have to open it for her
and I think I know how.
Tris. if we don't leave now.
we're not gonna get outta here.
I have to do this first.
Look. I know it doesn't make any sense.
but you have to trust me. please.
With my life. apparently.
All security teams.
be advised. breach in...
Do it.
Flank right.
Don't move!
Initializing Amity Sim.
Back again. are we?
You're an even bigger
fool than your mother.
Say whatever you want to me. Jeanine.
But I'm not gonna fight you.
How very Amity of you.
I mean it.
I'm not gonna fight you.
Of course you're not.
You're gonna fight her.
The one you really hate.
What are you?
I'm you. Tris.
I'm the real you.
I'm not gonna fight you.
I'll make you fight me.
You're not me.
I am.
I'm what they see when they look at you.
You killed Will.
And your parents.
You're deadly.
That's enough!
No one's gonna love you. Tris.
They're never even gonna miss you.
This world will be better off without you.
One less Divergent ruining everything.
And no one will ever.
ever forgive you for what you've done.
You're wrong.
Because I will.
Amity Sim complete.
Wait!
No! Stop!
Initializing message.
Hello.
I come from outside the wall.
Where we have all but destroyed each other.
We designed your city as an experiment.
We believe it is the only way
to recover the humanity we have lost.
And we created factions to ensure peace.
But we believe there
will be those among you
who will transcend these factions.
These will be the Divergent.
They are the true purpose
of this experiment.
They are vital to humanity's survival.
If you're watching this now.
then at least one of you is proof
that our experiment has succeeded.
The time has come for you
to emerge from your isolation
and rejoin us.
We've allowed you to believe
that you're the last of us.
But you're not.
Mankind waits for you
with hope
beyond the wall.
You okay?
Yeah.
You were wrong about us.
We were never the problem.
We're the solution.
Bury the box.
- What?
- No one sees it.
Ever.
Kill them both.
No!
Drop it! Now!
Don't move.
Down! Put your weapons down. now!
Drop them. Drop them.
Stay!
Put it down!
Do not move.
Hello. Jeanine.
Evelyn?
Impressive.
Think we're gonna like it here.
Do you honestly think the other factions
will stand for this?
Because you're so popular?
Get her out of here.
When that message gets out.
it'll be the end.
What message?
You'll see. I'm gonna put it
on every monitor in the city.
We have separated you from the rest of us.
And we created factions to ensure peace.
The time has come
to emerge from your
isolation and rejoin us.
We've allowed you to believe
that you're the last of us.
But you're not.
If you're watching this now.
then at least one of you is proof
that our experiment has succeeded.
Mankind waits for you. with hope.
beyond the wall.
These will be the Divergent.
They are the true purpose
of this experiment.
They are vital to humanity's survival.
You did it.
- Yeah.
Everyone's staring at me.
You changed everything.
What now?
Only one way to find out.
You ready?
It's been over 200 years.
Who knows what's out there?
You'll never find out.
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-